Guide to the Records of the Office of the President (Oliva) RG.3.0.11
New York University Archives
- Series VII. Governance, 1986-2002; 9.63 Linear Feet in 22 manuscript boxes
  - Committee on Gerontology and Geriatric Health Care, 1992 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Council on Community Service, 1994 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Curricular Development Challenge Fund Committee, 1999 (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Deans' and Vice Presidents' Meetings, 1990-2001 (Box 102, Folder 12-13)
  - EQUAL Commission, 1994-1999 (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Council, 1991-2001 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences Meetings, 1991-2001 (Box 103, Folder 2-4)
  - Federal Relations Report, 1992 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Dean's Council, 1996-1997 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Glucksman Ireland House, 1998 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Humanities Council, 1986-2001 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Insitute of Fine Arts (IFA) Board of Trustees, 1990-1991 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Insitute of Fine Arts (IFA) Board of Trustees, 1992 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Insitute of Fine Arts (IFA) Board of Trustees, 1993-1996 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Insitute of Fine Arts (IFA) Board of Trustees, 1997-2002 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - (Villa) La Pietra Planning Group, 1994-1999 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1991-1992 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1993-1994 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1995 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1996-1997 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1998 (Box 105, Folder 2-5)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 1999 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 2000 (Box 106, Folder 2-3)
  - Medical Center Board of Trustees, 2001 (Box 106, Folder 4, Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools, 1990-1994 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Office of Legal Counsel, 1991 (Box 107, Folder 3-4)
  - Office of Legal Counsel, 1992-2002 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Parents Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Resource Planning Group, 1993 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - School of Continuing Education Center for Publishing Studies Board of Advisers, 1997 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - School of Law Foundation Board of Trustees, 1988-1999 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - School of Law Foundation Board of Trustees, 2000 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - School of Law Foundation Board of Trustees, 2001 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Science Council, 1991-1995 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Senior Vice President, 1994-1995 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Stern School of Business Board of Overseers, 1992-1996 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Student Senators Council, 1992-2000 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Study Group on Increasing the Ethnic Diversity of the University, 1990 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Tisch School of the Arts Dean's Council Dinner, 1994 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - University Animal Welfare Committee, 1993-1996 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - University Commission on European Studies, 1993 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - University Senate, 1988-1990 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - University Senate, 1991 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - University Senate, 1992 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - University Senate, 1993 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - University Senate, 1994 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - University Senate, 1995 (Box 109, Folder 5, Box 110, Folder 1)
  - University Senate, 1996 (Box 110, Folder 2-5, Box 111, Folder 1)
  - University Senate, 1997 (Box 111, Folder 2-4)
  - University Senate, 1998 (Box 111, Folder 5, Box 112, Folder 1-2)
  - University Senate, 1999 (Box 112, Folder 3-5)
  - University Senate, 2000 (Box 113, Folder 1-3)
  - University Senate, 2001 (Box 113, Folder 4-5, Box 114, Folder 1)
  - University Senate, 2002 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - University-Wide Planning Commission, 1988 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Vice President for External Affairs, 1992-1998 (Box 114, Folder 4)
- Series VIII. Schools, Offices, and Divisions, 1986-2002; 4.81 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes
  This series includes correspondence, budgets, admissions statistics, and annual reports collected by the Office of the President on individual NYU Schools and Divisions, including the Office of Undergraduate Admissions, NYU Medical Center, and Tisch School of the Arts, among others. It illustrates Oliva's interaction and involvement with every aspect of the university, academic and administrative.
  - Book Centers, 1993-2001 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Casa Italiana, 1993-1999 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - College of Arts and Sciences -- Office of the Dean, 1990-2000 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - College of Dentistry, 1991-1998 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - C-Team (NYU Student Community Volunteers), 1992-1995 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Department of Athletics, Intramurals, and Recreation, 1991-2002 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Faculty of Arts and Science (FAS) -- Office of the Dean, 1990-1991 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - FAS -- Office of the Dean, 1992 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - FAS -- Office of the Dean, 1993-2002 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - FAS -- Office of the Vice Chancellor, 1993 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - FAS -- Office of the Vice Chancellor, 1994 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - FAS -- Office of the Vice Chancellor, 1995-1996 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - FAS -- Africana Studies Proposal, 1992 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - FAS -- Center for Latin American and Caribbean Studies, 1992 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - FAS -- Center for Neural Science, 1988-1992 (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - FAS -- Department of Anthropology, 1999 (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - FAS -- Department of Applied Science, 1993 (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - FAS -- Department of Chemistry, 1989-2000 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - FAS -- Department of French, 1992-1993 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - FAS -- Department of French, 1994-1999 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - FAS -- Department of History, 1997-2000 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - FAS -- Department of Journalism and Mass Communication, 1991-1995 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - FAS -- Department of Politics, 1995-1998 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - FAS -- Department of Psychology, 1994 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - FAS -- European Studies, 1991 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - FAS -- The Hagop Kevorkian Center for Near Eastern Studies, 1992 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - FAS -- Medieval and Renaissance Studies Program, 1997-1999 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - FAS -- Office of the Dean for Science, 1991-1996 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study -- Office of the Dean, 1992-1999 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study -- Creative Arts Team, 1992-1996 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Glucksman Ireland House, 1991-2001 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science (GSAS) -- Office of the Dean, 1992-1996 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - GSAS -- Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1992-1998 (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Grey Art Gallery and Study Center, 1998-1999 (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Human Resources Division, 1991-2001 (Box 117, Folder 16)
  - Insitute of Fine Arts -- Office of the Director, 1992-2001 (Box 117, Folder 17)
  - NYU Libraries, 1991-1999 (Box 117, Folder 18)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Institutional Advancement, 1990-1992 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Institutional Advancement, 1993 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Institutional Advancement, 1994 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Institutional Advancement, 1995 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Academic Development, 1986-1997 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Vice President for Academic Development, 1998-2001 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Faculty Resource Network, 1990-1994 (Box 119, Folder 1-2)
  - Office of Academic Affairs/Development -- Institute of Afro-American Affairs, 1987-1993 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Office of Administration, 1991-1993 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Office of Administration, 1994-1995 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Office of Administration, 1996-2001 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Office of the Deputy Chancellor, 1991-1996 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Office of Equal Opportunity, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Office of Enrollment Services/Admissions, 1991-1993 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Office of Enrollment Services/Admissions, 1994-1997 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Office of Enrollment Services/Admissions, 1998 (Box 120, Folder 4-5)
  - Office of Enrollment Services/Admissions, 1999 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Office of Enrollment Services/Admissions, 2000-2001 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Office of External Affairs -- University Development and Alumni Giving, 1993-2000 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Office of External Affairs -- University Relations and Public Affairs, 1990-1993 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Office of External Affairs -- University Relations and Public Affairs, 1994-1995 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Office of External Affairs -- University Relations and Public Affairs, 1996-2001 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Office of External Affairs -- Vice President, 1991-1993 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Office of External Affairs -- Vice President, 1994-1995 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Office of External Affairs -- Vice President, 1996-2002 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Office of the Provost, 1991-1998 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Office of the Provost, 1999-2001 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Office of Sponsored Programs, 1991-2001 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Office of Student Affairs -- Vice President, 1991-1993 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Office of Student Affairs -- Vice President, 1994 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - Office of Student Affairs -- Vice President, 1995-2002 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - Office of the University Registrar, 1994-2001 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - The Onassis Center for Hellenic Studies, 1990-1996 (Box 123, Folder 5, Box 124, Folder 1)
  - President Emeritus -- Brademas, John, 1990-1995 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Remarque Institute, 1996-1999 (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, 1990-2000 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - School of Continuing Education/Continuing and Professional Studies, 1992-2001 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - School of Education, 1989-1993 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - School of Education, 1994-2001 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - School of Law, 1990-2000 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - School of Medicine/Medical Center, 1990-2001 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - School of Social Work, 1991-1995 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Stern School of Business, 1990-2001 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Tisch School of the Arts, 1991-2001 (Box 125, Folder 4)
- Series IX. Publicity, 1986-2002; 3.33 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 2 oversized flat boxes
  This series reflects the Office of the President's interaction with the public about NYU. It includes Public Affairs Office material related to Oliva's appearances and events; printed matter (clippings and articles on Oliva, NYU in general, and other individuals associated with NYU); press releases; and NYU publications (individual school brochures; event flyers; conference programs; and issues of Service Matters and NYU Today).
  - Public Affairs Office, 1986-1992 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Public Affairs Office, 1993 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Public Affairs Office, 1994-1995 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Public Affairs Office, 1996-2001 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Clippings and Interviews with Oliva, 1986-1993 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Clippings and Interviews with Oliva, 1994-2001 (Box 127, Folder 1, Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Clippings on NYU Individuals and Programs, 1990-1993 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Clippings on NYU Individuals and Programs, 1994-1995 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Clippings on NYU Individuals and Programs, 1996-2001 (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1990-1996 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1997-2002 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - NYU Publications, 1987-1991 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - NYU Publications, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 3-4)
  - NYU Publications, 1993-1994 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - NYU Publications, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - NYU Publications, 1996-1998 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - NYU Publications, 1999 (Box 129, Folder 3, Box 130, Folder 2)
  - NYU Publications, 2000-2002 (Box 129, Folder 4)
- Series X. Art and Memorabilia, circa 1960-2002; 6.81 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 media box, and 8 oversized flat boxes
  This series consists of artwork and objects gifted to Oliva; photographs that presumably hung in Oliva's office; and memorabilia, such as a graduation robe, a C-Team T-shirt, and a flag flown over the Kimmel Center in honor of September 11.
  Arranged chronologically by box and folder number.
  - Photograph of Washington Square Arch, circa 1990s (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Caricature (Drawing) of Oliva, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Drawing of the Library of New York University (Unknown Artist), undated (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of Tommy Lasorda, Inscribed and Signed, undated (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Signed Tribute Poster to Oliva, 2002 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Caricatures (Photographs) of Oliva, undated (Box 130, Folder 3-5)
  - Signed Guest Book, 1994-1995 (Box 131)
  - Photograph of Oliva with Unidentified Person, circa 1990-1995 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of Queen Sofia of Spain, Inscribed and Signed, 2000 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of Bullfighter, Jesus Arias, Inscribed and Signed, undated (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - C-Team T-Shirt, undated (Box 134)
  - Escutcheons of NYU, undated (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Sir Harold Acton, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Photograph from U. S. Capitol Historical Society, circa 1960s (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Flag Flown over Kimmel Construction Site on September 11, 2001 (Box 136)
  - Ceremonial Robe, undated (Box 140)
  - Thank You Pins, undated (Box 141)
  - Ceremonial Plate, undated (Box 141)
- Series XI. Subject Files, 1975-2002; 1.31 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes
  This series contains printed matter on topics of interest to Oliva, used either as research (such as Russia) or related to his role as university president (such as higher education and tuition). Most of the materials consist of published articles, clippings, and books.
  - Academic Freedom, 1995-2002 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - AIDS, 1987-1994 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Astin, Alexander, et al. -- The American Freshman: National Norms for Fall 1990 (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Beach, Elizabeth -- "'Out of the Box:' Thinking about the Training of Lawyers in the Next Millennium", July 2000 (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Business Schools, 1987 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Califano, Joseph A., Jr. -- The Enduring Legacy of Lyndon Johnson…"The Ship Sails On", May 1999 (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Catholic Schools, 1983-1984 (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - College Athletics, 1985-1992 (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - College Presidents, circa 1997 (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University, circa 1990-1995 (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - Core Curriculum, 1990 (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, 1983 (Box 137, Folder 12)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1986-1994 (Box 137, Folder 13)
  - Czech Literature and Culture, 1990 (Box 137, Folder 14)
  - Early Childhood Education, 1996 (Box 137, Folder 15)
  - Flamm, Donald -- "An Idea for Peace in the Middle East", 1993 (Box 137, Folder 16)
  - Gopal, Sarvepalli -- Jawaharlal Nehru: A Biography, Vols. 1-3, 1975-1984 (Box 137, Folder 17, Box 138, Folder 1-2)
  - Grants, 1990 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Greenwich Village, 1990 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Higher Education, 1982-1995 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Hospitals, 1990 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - La Carta Perduta: Paolo dal Pozzo Toscanelli e la Cartografia delle Grandi Scoperte, 1992 (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Liberal Arts, 1983-1984 (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Manley, Albert E. -- A Legacy Continues: The Manley Years at Spelman College, 1953-1976, 1995 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - New York City Politics, 1993-1995 (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Other Universities, 1991-1996 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Poetry and Quotes, undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Russia, circa 1987-1992 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Seward Park High School, 1990 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Students, 1983-1987 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - Teens, 1990 (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - Title IX, 1987-1989 (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Tuition, 1993 (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - U. S. Deficit, 1993 (Box 139, Folder 11)